Deception. The greatest weapon in war.
Operation Mincemeat is a war, history, drama film directed by John Madden.
In 1943, two British intelligence officers concoct Operation Mincemeat, wherein their plan to drop a corpse with false papers off the coast
of Spain would fool Nazi spies into believing the Allied forces were planning to attack by way of Greece rather than Sicily.
Ewen Montagu, played by Colin Firth.
Charles Cholmondeley, played by Matthew Macfadyen.
Jean Leslie, played by Kelly Macdonald.
Hester Leggett, played by Penelope Wilton.
Ian Fleming, played by Johnny Flynn.
Admiral John Godfrey, played by Jason Isaacs.
Operation Mincemeat, subtitled The True Spy Story that Changed the Course of
World War II, is a 2021 war drama film directed by John Madden.
It is based upon Ben Macintyre's 2010 book, also called Operation Mincemeat, on
the British Operation Mincemeat during the Second World War.
The film stars Colin Firth, Kelly Macdonald, Matthew Macfadyen, James
Fleet, Penelope Wilton, Johnny Flynn and Jason Isaacs.
This was Paul Ritter's final film appearance, and was dedicated to his memory.
Operation Mincemeat had its world premiere at the 2021 British Film Festival in Australia,
and was released in the United Kingdom on 15 April 2022 by Warner Bros.
It was released on Netflix in North American and
South American countries on 11 May 2022.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
$15.7 million worldwide against a $6.3 million budget.
The film explores themes of sicily, italy, spy, world
war ii, based on true story, remake.
The tone is emotional.